Preliminary Guide to the Lionel Barrow Papers, 1940-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2010-0079), 1940-2000s, (15 boxes)
  - Name and Subject clippings/files (Box 21)
    - Louis Martin (Box 21)
    - Gregory Hines (Box 21)
    - Spike Lee (Box 21)
    - Oscar Micheaox (Box 21)
    - Gordon Parks (Box 21)
    - Mario Van Peebles (Box 21)
    - Sidney Poitier (Box 21)
    - Ted Poston (Box 21)
    - Raspberry, William (Box 21)
    - Paul Robeson (3 folders) (Box 21)
    - Tim Reid (Box 21)
    - Calvin Rolark (UBF) (Box 21)
    - Rowan, Carl (Box 21)
    - Robert Townsend (Box 21)
    - Denzel Washington (Box 21)
    - Keenan Wayans (Box 21)
    - Ben Wright (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Women in media (22 folders) (Box 21)
    - NBMC meeting, 1980 (Box 21)
    - Barbados (Box 21)
    - Education (Box 21)
    - Health (3 folders) (Box 21)
    - NASADAD (Box 21)
    - NAIC (Box 21)
    - Clearinghouse (Box 21)
    - Rehab Brief (Box 21)
    - Federal Agency-Forms, contracts (Box 21)
    - Health-history of Blacks, health care (Box 21)
    - Cancer (Box 21)
  - Name and Subject clippings/files (Box 22)
    - National Conference on Hypertension Control, 1975 (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Politics (Box 22)
    - NARIC (National Rehab Information Center) (Box 22)
    - Mental health (Box 22)
    - Health (3 folders) (Box 22)
    - Racism, anti-semitism, apartheid (Box 22)
    - Racism, clippings (Box 22)
    - Bigotry (Box 22)
  - Daytimers (plastic boxes with day schedules/notes), 1994-2000 (Box 22)
  - Clippings/subject files related to Minorities and the Media course (Box 23)
  - Blacks in broadcasting (6 folders) (Box 23)
  - Roots (Box 23)
  - Blacks in the communication industry (Box 23)
  - Minority views of media course (8 folders) (Box 23)
  - Source materials (Box 23)
  - Wilhelmina Barrows-American Red Cross materials, 1940s (Box 24)
    - Red Cross publications and booklets, 1940s (Box 24)
    - Magazines: Overseas Woman, 1945 (Box 24)
    - Program reports-Army Rest Centers, 1946 (Box 24)
    - Wilhelmina Barrows official documents, 1945-1947 (Box 24)
    - Club training-reference materials, 1945-1947 (Box 24)
    - Post-war transport newspapers, The Crow's Nest, 1946 (Box 24)
    - Returning soldier information, 1945-1946 (Box 24)
    - At Your Service publications, 1946 (Box 24)
    - Yank and other army-related publications, 1945-1946 (Box 24)
    - Airline pamphlets and souvenirs, 1940s (Box 24)
    - Italy guides and postcards, 1940s (3 folders) (Box 24)
    - France guides and postcards, 1940s (3 folders) (Box 24)
    - French speaking guides, 1940s (Box 24)
    - Other guides and postcards, 1940s (Box 24)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1940s (Box 24)
  - Wilhelmina Barrows materials (Box 25)
    - National Council of Negro Women materials, 1950s-1960s (Box 25)
    - NCNW Resolutions, booklets, 1953-1954 (Box 25)
    - NCNW Report, 1953-1957, 1957 (Box 25)
    - NCNW newspaper clippings, 1954 (Box 25)
    - Morehouse College mailings, 1960s (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, 1940s-1970s (Box 25)
    - Clippings, international news and United Nations coverage, 1940s-1960s (Box 25)
  - Photographs and albums (Box 26)
- Accession (2010-0144), (4 boxes)
  This addition includes Barrow's speeches, writings, and research files regarding advertising, African Americans in the marketing profession, and minorities in journalism. It also includes materials from his time as a student, at Morehouse College and as a Ph.D. candidate at the University of Wisconsin. Along with industry reports, his writings also include creative fiction and essays.
  Other significant components of this addition are Barrow's materials from his army service during the Korean War, dating from 1950-1951. The majority of this material is correspondence to his mother, Wilhelmina Barrow, which frequently includes copies of articles or press releases he's written while stationed overseas. Barrow wrote about his regiment, the 24th Infantry, and it being desegregated while he was enlisted; he also frequently wrote about the slow mail delivery and the unreliable payment of his wages.
  The remainder of the addition includes more research files from Barrow's unfinished book on the Freedom's Journal, as well as photographs, dated from 1982-1984. The photographs document both personal and professional events. A list of topics is included within the box.
  - Speeches and writings (12 folders) (Box 27)
  - Cecil Elombe Brath, Color Us Cullud: American Negro Leadership Official Coloring Book, 1963 (Box 27)
  - AEJMC (Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication) files, including research files and committee work on minorities in journalism (8 folders) (Box 27)
  - Research files on minorities and marketing/advertising (especially regarding African Americans and employment) (7 folders) (Box 27)
  - Ph.D. proposal and notes, 1960 (9 folders) (Box 27)
  - School files, creating writing and essays, 1940s-1970s (4 folders) (Box 28)
  - Korean War materials
    - Army enlistment, reporting and journalism, 1950 July-August (Box 28)
    - Letters, writings, press releases (by Barrow), 1950 August-December (3 folders) (Box 28)
    - Photographs and captions, 1950-1951 (Box 28)
    - Letters, writings, press releases (by Barrow), 1951 (Box 28)
    - Wilhelmina Barrow's incoming correspondence regarding Lionel Barrow, 1951 September-October (Box 28)
    - Chairborne Infantry, 1951 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence to Wilhelmina Barrow, 1960s (Box 28)
  - 24th Infantry reflagging, 2001 (Box 28)
  - Research files (2 folders) (Box 28)
  - Foote, Cone, and Belding materials, 1960s (3 folders) (Box 28)
  - Reports on marketing in movies (Box 28)
  - Remarks, AEJMC summer internship program, 1988 (Box 28)
  - Minority groups in marketing, 1969 (Box 28)
  - 4-As project, New York Council (Box 28)
  - Minority Media Means Money, 1971 (Box 28)
  - Is there a future for blacks in business communication? (Box 28)
  - Dreyfuss Affair commentary, 1976 (Box 28)
  - American Association for Public Opinion research, 1974 (Box 28)
  - Unity Dem Club, 1960s (Box 28)
  - Afro Urban Institute, Inc., 1970s (Box 28)
  - Research files and drafts for Freedom's Journal book (4 folders) (Box 28)
  - Research files and drafts on Freedom's Journal (10 folders) (Box 29)
  - Research files on black press (Accordian Folder, with subjects A-Z) (Box 29)
  - Photograph topic list (Box 30)
  - Photographs, 1982-1984 (Box 30)